<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Gavin Tranquilino</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Gavin Tranquilino</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gavintranquilino.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>&lt;strong>Instrumented Knee Crutch&lt;/strong> @ University of Waterloo</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/ideas-clinic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/ideas-clinic/</guid><description>Project Gallery This project is displayed in a Google Photos album. Below you can browse through the photo gallery of the instrumented knee crutch project developed at the University of Waterloo IDEAS Clinic.
View Full Album About the Project The Instrumented Knee Crutch was developed as part of the IDEAS Clinic at the University of Waterloo. This project involved designing and building an instrumented crutch that could measure and provide feedback on weight bearing during rehabilitation.</description></item><item><title>Dishwasher &lt;br> Magnets 🧼🍽️</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/dishwasher-magnets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/dishwasher-magnets/</guid><description>Preview The Problem At home, the dishwasher can either have dirty dishes, clean dishes, or currently running.
There have been countless times that one of us in the house put dirty dishes when the dishwasher had clean ones, or someone accidentally opened the dishwasher in the middle of its current cycle.
How can we tell whether or not the dishwasher was clean, dirty, or still running?
Initial Solutions For the first few weeks since we realized this was a recurring problem, my mom placed a sticky note that says the dishes were clean.</description></item><item><title>&lt;strong>Custom Tamagotchi&lt;/strong></title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/circle-display/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/circle-display/</guid><description>The Goal Make a portable handheld virtual pet that can support higher quality images on a round display.
My current plan is to turn my stuffed animals into virtual pets I can take around with me as if it were a Tamagotchi.
I am also a fan of the idea to introduce various sensors and an IMU to increase possible interactions with my pets.
I think this is really cool to carry around as a wearable and fun to showcase to others as well.</description></item><item><title>Calendar Compare 📅</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/calendar-compare/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/calendar-compare/</guid><description>Calendar Compare 📅 Sign in with google, import your calendars and find when you and your friends are free!
W Stage Pic Winning Selfie Wacom Tablet &amp;#43; JBL Speaker?? &amp;#10094; &amp;#10095; Inspiration I&amp;rsquo;m sure we all know the pain of trying to meet up with friends or trying to organize anything in general, and just never being able to find the time to do it. No matter what you do, it seems like everyone is busy, and by the time you actually find a day that works, it&amp;rsquo;s taken way longer than it needs to, and that&amp;rsquo;s putting it lightly.</description></item><item><title>C++ shitpost vid</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/trying-cpp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/trying-cpp/</guid><description>C++ shitpost vid The Video Granted access to Premiere Pro, I tried actually editing for once.
I am not particularly interested in editing videos, but here&amp;rsquo;s my attempt.
So enjoy this random shitpost + brainrot programming meme video.
What&amp;rsquo;s the Point? This is basically my test run of &amp;ldquo;could i be a youtuber?&amp;rdquo;
I learned editing sucks, takes too much time, and I&amp;rsquo;d rather keep a blog updated lol.
Heavily edited &amp;ldquo;Mr.</description></item><item><title>mathemati.co</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/mathematico/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/mathematico/</guid><description>mathemati.co deerhacks 2024 The Demo Overview I am getting too tired&amp;hellip; we already covered what it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to do. Just check it down below.
DevPost GitHub</description></item><item><title>Blink Twice 👀 If You Need Help</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/blink-twice-if-you-need-help/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/blink-twice-if-you-need-help/</guid><description>Blink Twice 👀 If You Need Help Full Project Demo Overview Blink Twice if You Need Help is a wearable computer vision enabled device.
The premise is simple, if you were in a hostage situation where calling 911 on your phone is too risky, you could use a blink detection system to call for help.
The idea started off as a joke. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen TikToks where people made the wildest videos and in the comments, they ask if they were forced to make the lame video and if they could blink twice if they need help.</description></item><item><title>&lt;strong>Mechanical Engineering&lt;/strong> @ Sheartak Tools</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/sheartak/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/sheartak/</guid><description>Overview I worked on&amp;hellip;
Using SolidWorks to model custom spiral cutterhead upgrades for clients&amp;rsquo; planers and jointers.
Creating custom user manuals based on parts lists for each model.
Making YouTube videos for tutorials and troubleshooting guides for various machines using Premiere and Photoshop.
Automating the process of creating mockup images for products using Photoshop actions.
An internal Python tool to help with stocking and keeping inventory in the warehouse.
Mechanical Engineering I worked on 15 customized woodworking cutterheads.</description></item><item><title>&lt;strong>Ri3D Crescendo&lt;/strong> @ University of Waterloo</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/ri3d-crescendo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/ri3d-crescendo/</guid><description>The Final Build! Check out what we made! Really proud of this robot given the time constraints and lack of members.
My Contributions I worked on the drivetrain and gearbox assembly, setting up and flashing the electronics, and 3D printing custom components.
Electronics Board Wiring the Electronics Shooter Mechanism Side View Full Robot Side View &amp;#10094; &amp;#10095; Overall, I had a lot of fun over these 3 days and honestly learned a lot along the way.</description></item><item><title>HackTheNorth 2023 &lt;strong>Psych Tracker&lt;/strong></title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/psych-tracker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/psych-tracker/</guid><description>HackTheNorth 2023 I had an incredible experience at HackTheNorth, Canada&amp;rsquo;s largest hackathon. The event at the University of Waterloo brought together 1,000 hackers from Canada and around the world. The HTN team did an amazing job, celebrating their 10th anniversary with custom stickers and unique digital tickets.
On top of trying to collect all the swag from the sponsors, I attended workshops and activities, including OpenAI, Intro to Embedded Systems, and Hacking the Brain workshops.</description></item><item><title>Python Code Jam 2023 &lt;strong>Benevolens&lt;/strong></title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/benevolens/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/benevolens/</guid><description>Python Discord Code Jam 2023 I participated in the Python Discord Code Jam, an annual event that provides an opportunity for individuals to collaborate on coding projects. A Code Jam is essentially a competition where participants are grouped into teams and given a specific programming task and theme to guide their project. They have a limited time frame, usually a little over a week, to create the best possible project based on the given theme and requirements.</description></item><item><title>Skills Ontario 2023 &lt;strong>Hockey Robot&lt;/strong></title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/hockey-robot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/hockey-robot/</guid><description>Skills Ontario Robotics Competition 2023 The Skills Ontario Competition is a prestigious event held annually in Ontario, Canada, that provides a platform for top students to showcase their skills and expertise in various vocational and technical fields. This competition spans over two and a half days and attracts participants, educators, families, and potential employers. Participants aim to prove that they are the best in their respective fields, competing in a wide range of skill-based contests.</description></item><item><title>VTuber &lt;br> 3D Printed Fanart</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/tfp3d/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/tfp3d/</guid><description>Tactical Fortnight Pyramid oh Tactical Fortnight Pyramid, divine,
your memes and vids, they heal this mind.
through every laugh, you pulled me through —
oh TFP, my thanks to you.
CHECK OUT HIS YOUTUBE IT'S SO PEEEAAAAAK His Character Design Front View Back View &amp;#10094; &amp;#10095; My 3D Fanart CAD Models: Using Fusion360, I created a 3D model of his pyramid Vtuber character design. The model is available right now on Thingiverse.</description></item><item><title>Light Switch &lt;br> Bot/Mount 💡</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/light-switch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/light-switch/</guid><description>Overview 3D printed, servo actuated, Raspberry Pi webserver, Discord API integration.
I wanted to create a device that can manually click the rocker switch of my room light on and off. I did not want to have to mess with any of the electrical circuits of the light switch system underneath the cover.
3D Printed Bracket The bracket I designed for the servo motor was modelled in Fusion360.
After learning the basics of CAD software, I was comfortable modelling the bracket on my own with precise measurements.</description></item><item><title>Rapid React 2022</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/rapid-react/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/rapid-react/</guid><description>This is 2702 Rebels&amp;rsquo; 2022 Rapid React Robot Rapid React? What that? My team, 2702 Rebels, is a FIRST Robotics FRC Team.
Every year, a new game is announced, and a team of highschool students, parents, and mentors work together to build robots to compete in these games. (Considered competitions). The competition is designed to inspire students to pursue careers in STEM (science, technology, engineering, and math) fields.
I was part of the Intake team, responsible for brainstorming, planning, modelling, and constructing the part of the robot that intakes and loads cargo, (the balls), into the robot.</description></item><item><title>&lt;strong>Roof Gutter Rain Mount&lt;/strong></title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/gutter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/gutter/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s this for? The roof rain gutter of my house dumps water straight onto the lawn.
This ruins the lawn right where the water is dumped.
We have a downspout tube to attach to the spout, but there is no good connection to the spout as there are two connected in parallel.
We could simply buy an adaptor to fit around 2 spouts, but I took the initiative to 3D print my own.</description></item><item><title>&lt;strong>Find Me Arrow&lt;/strong> Key Holder</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/its-right-here/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/its-right-here/</guid><description>What is this? Lame Norwegian friend was searching for a keychain for my &amp;ldquo;friend&amp;rdquo; poopwrld.
He was streaming his screen to the groupchat (Discord 🤢), and we found the funniest item on sale.
It was some random Norwegian site for gag items??
I thought it was such a random red arrow meme idea that I NEEDED to recreate it.
Norwegian Website Modelling in Fusion360 Slicer Preview with Supports &amp;#10094; &amp;#10095; 3D Printing I have a Kingroon KP3S, and I have really liked its performance.</description></item><item><title>&lt;strong>Automated&lt;/strong> Lamp</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/lamp-bot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/lamp-bot/</guid><description>Overview A simple LED lamp. Automated.
Lamp Bot Breadboard Setup Lamp Bot Perfboard Setup &amp;#10094; &amp;#10095; How Did I Do It? FYI: If you don&amp;rsquo;t already know, you can click the images to be redirected to either code or a video.
I am very proud of this project, mostly because I find it to be the most useful, despite its simplicity.
I rewired the lamp to a separate transistor switch circuit.</description></item><item><title>&lt;strong>Quadratics Solver&lt;/strong></title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/quadratics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/quadratics/</guid><description>What does it do? This quadratics solver app uses matplotlib to graph a quadratic equation. This application also solves the equation in vertex form, solves for the roots, and solves for the vertex.
Source Code # main.py from equation import Equation, graph def main(): # User input while True: try: a = int( input(&amp;#39;What is the &amp;#34;a&amp;#34; value of your equation? (in standard form):\n&amp;#39;) ) b = int(input(&amp;#39;&amp;#34;b&amp;#34; value? (in standard form):\n&amp;#39;)) c = int(input(&amp;#39;&amp;#34;c&amp;#34; value?</description></item><item><title>My Sticker/Clothing Store &lt;strong>Cravin' Vinyls&lt;/strong></title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/cravinvinyls/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/cravinvinyls/</guid><description>Cravin&amp;rsquo; Vinyls? Like many other great businesses, Cravin&amp;rsquo; Vinyls once started as an idea, a motive, a thought. I remember hearing about a small business grant for at least $1000 during COVID and wondered, &amp;ldquo;I should totally give this a shot!&amp;rdquo; Unfortunately, all my previous ideas for products and services quickly came to an abrupt stop. Soon after the grant had ended, I remembered my mom&amp;rsquo;s old cutting machine (which had been refurbished) and knew that I could make things with it.</description></item><item><title>&lt;strong>COVID-19&lt;/strong> Screening Bypass</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/covid-19-bypass/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/covid-19-bypass/</guid><description>What does it do? This program is a project I designed to quickly fill out the COVID-19 Screening Tool. Every time I went to school, I had to fill out the COVID-19 Screening Form as a proof that I can enter the building. The questions on the form are very straightforward and common sense. While this program is not intended to lie on the form, this was created to speed up the process of having to fill out a valid form every day.</description></item><item><title>&lt;strong>Remote-controlled&lt;/strong> LED</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/remote-led/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/remote-led/</guid><description>Project Demonstration Source Code #include &amp;lt;IRremote.h&amp;gt; #define MAX_TIME 150 IRrecv irrecv(6); decode_results results; long lastPressTime = 0; long ON_BUTTON = 16753245; long B_ONE = 16724175; long red = 255; long green = 255; long blue = 255; int redPin = 9; int greenPin = 10; int bluePin = 5; bool state = false; void RGB_colour(int red_val, int green_val, int blue_val) { // Function to output RGB values analogWrite(redPin, red_val); analogWrite(greenPin, green_val); analogWrite(bluePin, blue_val); } void setup() { Serial.</description></item><item><title>&lt;strong>Motion Sensor&lt;/strong></title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/motion-sensor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/motion-sensor/</guid><description>Project Demonstration This project was directly inspired by Paul McWhorter. This project was one of my first interactions with the Arduino.
Paul McWhorter's Video "with icon"</description></item><item><title>YouTube Viewbot</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/youtube-viewbot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/youtube-viewbot/</guid><description>This YouTube Viewbot uses Selenium for Python to view a Youtube video multiple times. This bot is not inteded to be used to gain thousands of views, but instead will aid in getting your first 100 views on a YouTube video.
How Does it Work? Once you run the program, the application will need user input to run. It asks for the video link, how many tabs to open, how long to watch the video for, and how many times it will watch the videos.</description></item><item><title>Sashiko &lt;br> Hitomezashi Stitching</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/hitomezashi-stitching/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/hitomezashi-stitching/</guid><description>SMHS Innovation Week During SMHS Innovation Week, students were challenged to explore creative problem solving through a variety of STEAM based activities. One of the optional challenges was to recreate traditional Hitomezashi stitching—a Japanese embroidery technique—using random patterns of 1s and 0s.
Instead of flipping coins or using a random number website as suggested, I decided to write my own program to generate the patterns digitally. This post documents how I built it, what I learned, and how traditional art can intersect with code.</description></item><item><title>This is my &lt;br> Wooden &lt;strong>CO2 Car&lt;/strong></title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/co2-car/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/co2-car/</guid><description>Mr. Renda&amp;rsquo;s CO2 Car Goal Draft, then woodwork a car to race against the rest of the class. Each car should be designed to fit the track, and also a location for the CO2 cartridge.
The Design Nothing too crazy. Just thought of a cool car design. No weight optimizations done. However, I do remember watching some Mark Rober video about how to win like slot cars or something, and that his tactic was to have weight concentrated at the back to start with more gravitational potential energy.</description></item><item><title>&lt;strong>GuhBot&lt;/strong> Discord Bot</title><link>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/guhbot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gavintranquilino.com/guhbot/</guid><description>Overview GuhBot (Derived from its owner GuhBean#6559), a Discord.py bot to add some action within your server. GuhBot is a major add-on for when you are looking to have some fun in your Discord server. This Discord bot adds unique features to your server such as, Fresh memes, an AI generated chatbot, Animated Emojis, Dice commands, COVID-19 statistics, Moderation, and so much more! GuhBot requires minimal setup, so it's beginner friendly for those new to Discord.</description></item></channel></rss>